Finding Aid for the Collection of Research Materials Related to Linguistic-Psychological Studies of Genie (pseudonym), 1895-2003, 1970-2003 LSC.0800
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 1. Audio visual materials, 1970-1993 (bulk 1970-1975); 44 boxes, 2 shoeboxes, and 2 oversize boxes
  - 1A. 1/2" video tapes, 1970-1977; 37 boxes
    - Reel no. 118, 1972 February 28, March 1 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      Following physical examination by Dr. Apthorp; Porch Test administered by G. Kinstler with Reba Braff and Marilyn Rigler.
    - Reel no. 119, 1972 March 1, 20 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      End of Porch Test administered by G. Kinstler with Reba Braff and Marilyn Rigler; JCC gymnasium.
    - Reel no. 120, 1972 April 15, May 5 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      With Dave Rigler fixing toilet; Genie in kitchen, helping Marilyn Rigler with dishes; discussion on spankings with Marilyn Rigler; singing, rhythm, spelling; Carol and Genie in the bedroom; backyard somersaults and swinging; David Rigler and Marilyn Rigler with Genie; toenail cutting; Marilyn Rigler reading a story to Genie.
    - Reel no. 121, 1972 May 6 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      Genie cooks an egg; having breakfast; chewing; television.
    - Reel no. 122, 1972 July 2, 4 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      Trip to cabin with family; exploring; speech therapy with Reba Braff; Caroline reading a story; Caroline spilled Genie's box of beads and Genie reacts with anger. VHS cassette copy available for reference in boxes 41 and 42.
    - Reel no. 123, 1972 July 4, 14 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      Continuation of Genie's reaction to spilt beads; Genie with others at IHM school. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 42.
    - Reel no. 124, 1972 July 13 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      Continuation of IHM school; children performing for TV; Genie and others in miscellaneous activities.
    - Reel no. 125, 1972 July 13 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      Continuation of IHM school; children outdoors at table for snack; doing art work; string painting; Genie plays with pan of water.
    - Reel no. 126, 1972 July 13 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      Continuation of IHM school; outdoors snack; painting.
    - Reel no. 127, 1972 September 3 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      With Steve and Pam; exercises; in swimming pool.
    - Reel no. 128, 1972 September 4 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      At the Riglers with Steve and Pam and friends; playing with two children with ball and Frisbee; reaction to children crying; using the video camera, picnic lunch.
    - Reel no. 129, 1972 September 4 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      At the Riglers with Steve and Pam and friends; examining dog house; playing ball; watching preparations for BBQ; throwing plastic top.
    - Reel no. 130, 1972 September 4 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      At the Riglers with Steve and Pam and friends; playing with children and ball; evening music and rhythm.
    - Reel no. 131, 1972 September 8, 9 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      Voice operated toy dog, Sessions I and II.
    - Reel no. 132, 1972 September 8 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      Voice operated toy dog, Session III
    - Reel no. 133, 1972 September 17, 20 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      Bogen and Neural and Street test; Marilyn Rigler and reading rewarded.
    - Reel no. 134, 1972 September 26 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      Number Concept test and Auditory Discrimination test with David Rigler. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 39.
    - Reel no. 135, 1972 November 4 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      Marilyn Rigler and discussion of Sesame Street magazine; reaction to Joel.
    - Reel no. 136, 1972 November 4 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      With Marilyn Rigler, lunch and discussing cars; feeding Tory.
    - Reel no. 137, 1972 November 9 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      Genie watching David Rigler assemble toy stove. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 42.
    - Reel no. 138, 1972 December 25; 1973 January 6 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      Mother's visit at Christmas; Genie eating cereal and looking at new shower curtain.
    - Reel no. 139, 1973 January 13 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      Reading lessons and penny reinforces.
    - Reel no. 140, 1973 January 24, 31; February 3 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      Susan Curtiss with Knox Cube test; additional linguistic tests; with Marilyn Rigler, typing. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 39.
    - Reel no. 141, 1973 February 7, 20; March 13, 24 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      Susan Curtiss linguistic testing; waiting for the school bus; loading the dishwasher; at Wiley house, exploring, eating lunch. VHS cassette copy available for reference in boxes 38 and 42.
    - Reel no. 142, 1973 March 24, 26 (Box 18, Folder 4)
      Continuation of no. 141. At Wiley house; having a bath; eating chocolate pudding. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 38.
    - Reel no. 143, 1973 April 8 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      Meal time with the Riglers; Genie's birthday party.
    - Reel no. 144, 1973 April 8 (Box 18, Folder 6)
      Genie's birthday party. Continuation of no. 143.
    - Reel no. 145, 1973 April 28; May 8,9 (Box 18, Folder 7)
      A home visit at mother's; testing in Palo Alto.
    - Reel no. 146, 1972 May 9 (Box 18, Folder 8)
      Continuation of testing at Palo Alto.
    - Reel no. 147, 1973 May 25 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      Genie and Marilyn Rigler work at CHLA office; verbal rep. to pictures; "reading" action words; draws picture; listening to story. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 42.
    - Reel no. 148, 1973 June 1 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      With Caroline at CHLA office, grammar lessons.
    - Reel no. 149, 1973 June 4 (Box 19, Folder 3)
      With Susan Curtiss at CHLA office, making questions and prepositions. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 42.
    - Reel no. 150, 1973 June 4 (Box 19, Folder 4)
      Continuation at CHLA with Susan Curtiss; review session. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 42.
    - Reel no. 151, 1973 June 5 (Box 19, Folder 5)
      With Marilyn Rigler doing exercises; using skin brushes.
    - Reel no. 152, 1973 June 6, 7 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      Continuation of no. 148. Lesson with Caroline at CHLA office; with Marilyn Rigler, describing pictures.
    - Reel no. 153, 1973 June 12 (Box 19, Folder 7)
      Visit by Hans Furth at the Rigler home; work at piano; tearing paper.
    - Reel no. 154, 1973 June 21; July 11 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      At the Riglers; spontaneous drawing; in the kitchen before school; feeling sad and agitated. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 42.
    - Reel no. 155, 1973 June 25 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      With Marilyn, exercising, skin brushed, pretending. With Jessalee [Beilby?], first movement session.
    - Reel no. 156, 1973 June 25 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      Continuation with Jessalee and movement.
    - Reel no. 157, 1973 June 26 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      With Sharon Hearn at CHLA office; reading; Sullivan Lessons.
    - Reel no. 158, 1973 June 28 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      Tested by Sue Knox; David Rigler and Reba Braff in office.
    - Reel no. 159, 1973 June 28 (Box 20, Folder 5)
      Continuation with David Rigler and Reba Braff; tantrum.
    - Reel no. 160, 1973 June 28; July 3 (Box 20, Folder 6)
      Tested by Sue Knox; lessons with Sharon Hearn at CHLA office.
    - Reel no. 161, 1973 July 3 (Box 20, Folder 7)
      Continuation with Sharon Hearn.
    - Reel no. 162, 1973 July 16 (Box 20, Folder 8)
      With Marilyn Rigler at CHLA office; skin brushes, exercises, rhythm. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 42.
    - Reel no. 163, 1973 July 23 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      Movement with Jessalee.
    - Reel no. 164, 1973 July 23 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      With Susan Curtiss at CHLA office; flannel boards, making questions and answers.
    - Reel no. 165, 1973 July 30 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Reel no. 166, 1973 August 9 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      With Sharon Hearn at CHLA office.
    - Reel no. 167, 1973 August 13, 20 (Box 21, Folder 5)
      With Susan Curtiss at CHLA office; testing plural nouns. Movement with Jessalee.
    - Reel no. 168, 1973 August 20 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Reel no. 169, 1973 August 27 (Box 21, Folder 7)
      Movement with Jessalee; beginning of a tantrum.
    - Reel no. 170, 1973 August 27 (Box 21, Folder 8)
      With Susan Curtiss at CHLA office, following tantrum. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 42.
    - Reel no. 171, 1973 September 17 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      Short session with Jessalee. Session with Susan Curtiss; new task; using "no" and "not"; forming answers on pocket board. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 43.
    - Reel no. 172, 1973 September 17, 24 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      Continuation of session with Susan Curtiss. With Sue Knox, working on stimulation (physical).
    - Reel no. 173, 1973 September 24 (Box 22, Folder 3)
      Continuation of physical therapy session with Sue Knox. Tape does not have sound.
    - Reel no. 174, 1973 September 30 (Box 22, Folder 4)
      Ruth Day (psychologist/psycholinguist from Yale) meets Genie at Riglers home.
    - Reel no. 175, 1973 November 5 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      Physical therapy session with Sue Knox.
    - Reel no. 176, 1973 November 8 (Box 22, Folder 6)
      Testing with Jeanne Block. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 39.
    - Reel no. 177, 1973 November 12 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      With Sue Knox' possible signs of dizziness.
    - Reel no. 178, 1973 November 19 (Box 22, Folder 8)
      Therapy and stimulation with Sue Knox. Balloon blowing and breath control.
    - Reel no. 179, 1973 November 21 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      In the kitchen, before school. Discussing Christmas; coping with delay in gratification. Susan Curtiss administers Furth Form test. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 43.
    - Reel no. 180, 1973 November 26 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      With Sue Knox. Exercises interrupted by two people dressed as animals; Smoky the Bear, and Owl. Jean Butler is with the animals.
    - Reel no. 181, 1973 November 28 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      With Susan Curtiss at the CHLA office; looking at semantic features. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 43.
    - Reel no. 182, 1974 February 3 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      David Rigler instructing in reading and writing; Cal Tech tachistoscope.
    - Reel no. 183, 1973 December 12 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      With Susan Curtiss; testing prepositions, tenses, relational terms, phonemic distinctions. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 39.
    - Reel no. 184, 1973 December 12 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      Continuation of no. 183.
    - Reel no. 185, 1973 December 17 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      Physical therapy and stimulation with Sue Knox. Mood and delay fluxations; pushing herself on scooter board with bag over her head.
    - Reel no. 186, 1973 December 19 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      Reading and writing with Sharon Hearn, at CHLA. Example of teaching method; how to remember.
    - Reel no. 187, 1973 December 20 (Box 24, Folder 1)
      Sharon Hearn teaching matching initial consonants.
    - Reel no. 188, 1973 December 26 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      Physical therapy and stimulation with Sue Knox.
    - Reel no. 189, 1974 January 2 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      Susan Curtiss tests using selected items from Auditory Test for Language Comprehension (an aphasia test); conjunction, disjunction comprehension, comparative and superlative, and relational terms. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 43.
    - Reel no. 190, 1974 January 11 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Reel no. 191, 1974 January 11, 21 (Box 24, Folder 5)
      Continuation of no. 190.
    - Reel no. 192, 1974 January 16 (Box 24, Folder 6)
      With Susan Curtiss; testing.
    - Reel no. 193, 1974 January 17 (Box 24, Folder 7)
      Making pudding; Marilyn pretends to be mama, Genie pretends to be the baby. Marilyn feeds Genie cereal. Additional description: "Genie has for some time been very interested in the Mixmaster. Marilyn Rigler has tried to channel this interest in a functional way." VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 43.
    - Reel no. 194, 1974 January 23 (Box 24, Folder 8)
      Testing with Susan Curtiss; personal pronouns subtests A and B, active voice, quantifiers.
    - Reel no. 195, 1974 January 28 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Reel no. 196, 1974 January 30, 31 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      Genie listens to Susan Curtiss play piano; Curtiss feeds Susan cereal.
    - Reel no. 197, 1974 February 4 (Box 25, Folder 3)
      Part 1 of testing battery administered by Cecile Falk: WISC.
    - Reel no. 198, 1974 February 4 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      Part 2 of testing battery administered by Cecile Falk: WISC.
    - Reel no. 199, 1974 February 4 (Box 25, Folder 5)
      Part 3 of testing battery administered by Cecile Falk: WISC.
    - Reel no. 200, 1974 February 4 (Box 25, Folder 6)
      Part 4 of testing battery administered by Cecile Falk: Peabody Picture Vocabulary test.
    - Reel no. 201, 1974 February 4 (Box 25, Folder 7)
      Part 5 of testing battery administered by Cecile Falk: Leiter International Performance Scale.
    - Reel no. 202, 1974 February 4, 5 (Box 25, Folder 8)
      Part 5 of testing battery administered by Cecile Falk: Leiter International Performance Scale. Testing occurred on first part of second day.
    - Reel no. 203, 1974 February 4 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Reel no. 204, 1974 February 5 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      Part 2 of second day of testing battery administered by Cecile Falk: Leiter International Performance Scale.
    - Reel no. 205, 1974 February 5 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      Part 3 of second day of testing battery administered by Cecile Falk: Leiter International Performance Scale, Stanford-Binet.
    - Reel no. 206, 1974 February 5 (Box 26, Folder 4)
      Part 4 of second day of testing battery administered by Cecile Falk: Stanford-Binet. Additional description: "At lunch Genie lost some plastic; thus, afternoon testing was more anxiety-ridden."
    - Reel no. 207, 1974 February 5 (Box 26, Folder 5)
      Part 5 of second day of testing battery administered by Cecile Falk: Stanford-Binet.
    - Reel no. 208, 1974 February 5, 22 (Box 26, Folder 6)
      Part 6 of second day of testing battery administered by Cecile Falk; physical therapy and stimulation with Sue Knox. Additional description: testing "ends on a positive note with interaction from David Rigler."
    - Reel no. 209, 1973 October 1 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Reel no. 210, 1974 February 11 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Reel no. 211, 1974 February 12 (Box 27, Folder 1)
      Part 1 of third day of testing battery administered by Cecile Falk: Illinois Test of Psycholinguistic Ability.
    - Reel no. 212, 1974 February 12 (Box 27, Folder 2)
      Part 2 of third day of testing battery administered by Cecile Falk: Illinois Test of Psycholinguistic Ability.
    - Reel no. 213, 1974 February 12 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      Part 3 of third day of testing battery administered by Cecile Falk: Illinois Test of Psycholinguistic Ability.
    - Reel no. 214, 1974 February 20 (Box 27, Folder 4)
      Susan Curtiss tests on active voice, word order, pronouns.
    - Reel no. 215, 1974 January 21; February 25 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Reel no. 216, 1974 March 7 (Box 27, Folder 6)
      With Susan Curtiss.
    - Reel no. 217, 1974 March 11, 18 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Reel no. 218, 1974 March 18, 25 (Box 27, Folder 8)
      Physical therapy and stimulation with Sue Knox. Continued on no. 220.
    - Reel no. 219, 1974 July 24 (Box 28, Folder 1)
      Marina McIntyre and Genie working with sign at Northridge.
    - Reel no. 220, 1974 March 25; April 6 (Box 28, Folder 2)
      Continuation of no. 218.
    - Reel no. 226, 1974 May 31 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - No reel number given, 1974 April 4 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      Larry Solow teaches Genie to sign; bad cold.
    - Reel no. 221, 1974 April 15 (Box 28, Folder 4)
      With Sue Knox.
    - No reel number given, 1974 April 16 (Box 28, Folder 5)
      First trials of EEG testing.
    - Reel no. 222, 1974 April 18 (Box 28, Folder 6)
      Larry Solow teaches Genie to sign; Genie's birthday. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 43.
    - Reel no. 223, 1974 April 23-24 (Box 28, Folder 7)
      Genie mixing pudding; Susan Curtiss playing piano while Genie listens. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 43.
    - Reel no. 224, 1974 May 13 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Reel no. 225, 1974 May 15 (Box 29, Folder 1)
      Genie and Marina McIntyre work with sign.
    - Reel no. 227, 1974 June 21 (Box 29, Folder 3)
      Larry Solow teaches Genie to sign. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 43.
    - Reel no. 228, 1974 June 21, 25 (Box 29, Folder 4)
      Continuation of no. 227.
    - Reel no. 229, 1974 June 25 (Box 29, Folder 5)
      Continuation of no. 228.
    - Reel no. 230, 1974 June 25 (Box 29, Folder 6)
      Reading with Sharon Hearn at the CHLA office.
    - Reel no. 231, 1974 June 25-26 (Box 29, Folder 7)
      Continuation of no. 230.
    - Reel no. 232, 1974 June 26 (Box 29, Folder 8)
      Larry Solow teaches Genie to sign.
    - Reel no. 233, 1974 June 26 (Box 30, Folder 1)
      Larry Solow teaches Genie to sign; reading with Sharon Hearn.
    - Reel no. 234, 1974 June 27 (Box 30, Folder 2)
      Last reading lesson with Sharon Hearn.
    - Reel no. 235, 1974 June 27; July 1 (Box 30, Folder 3)
      Continuation of no. 234. Sue Knox attempts to test Genie and is unsuccessful.
    - Reel no. 236, 1974 July 8 (Box 30, Folder 4)
      Sue Knox tests Genie.
    - Reel no. 236, 1974 July 1, 8 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Reel no. 237, 1974 July 15 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Reel no. 238, 1974 July 15 (Box 30, Folder 7)
      Sue Knox administers tests for Genie.
    - Reel no. 239, 1974 July 17 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Reel no. 240, 1974 July 17 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - No reel number given, 1974 July 19 (Box 31, Folder 2)
      Larry Solow teaching Genie to sign.
    - Reel no. 241, 1974 July 31 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Reel no. 242, 1974 August 26 (Box 31, Folder 4)
      Physical therapy with Sue Knox.
    - No reel number given, 1874 September 16 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - No reel number given, 1974 December 2 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - No reel number given, 1974 December 13 (Box 31, Folder 7)
      Genie at a dental exam.
    - No reel number given, 1974 December 30 (Box 31, Folder 8)
      Cecile Falk administers WISC tests.
    - No reel number given, 1975 January 29 (Box 31, Folder 9)
      Genie sews on Marilyn Rigler's sewing machine. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 38.
    - Reel no. 401, 1975 June 25-26 (Box 32, Folder 1)
      UCLA Rapid Naming test.
    - Reel no. 402, 1977 September 29 (Box 32, Folder 2)
      Genie with the Riglers.
    - Reel no. 403, 1975 January 3 (Box 32, Folder 3)
      Cecile Falk administers Stanford Binet test.
    - Reel no. 404, 1975 January 3 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Reel no. 405, 1975 January 3 (Box 32, Folder 5)
      Cecile Falk administers Stanford Binet test; PPVT.
    - Reel no. 406, 1975 January 2 (Box 32, Folder 6)
      Therapy with Sue Knox.
    - Reel no. 407, 1975 January 3 (Box 32, Folder 7)
      Cecile Falk administers tests.
    - Reel no. 408, 1975 January 3 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Reel no. 409, 1975 January 3 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Reel no. 410, 1975 February 12 (Box 33, Folder 2)
      Larry Solow and Genie.
    - Reel no. 411, 1975 June 27 (Box 33, Folder 3)
      Larry Solow tests Genie on sign.
    - Reel no. 412, 1977 June 20 (Box 33, Folder 4)
      Genie at CHLA office; Marilyn Rigler. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 43.
    - Reel no. 413, 1975 February 12 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Reel no. 414, no date (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Reel no. 415, 1977 July 8 (Box 33, Folder 7)
      Face puppets.
    - Reel no. 416, 1974 April 5 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Reel no. 417, 1977 June 24 (Box 34, Folder 1)
      Therapy session with the Riglers, focused on Genie's closed mouth and dentistry. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 43.
    - Reel no. 418, 1977 September 15 (Box 34, Folder 2)
      Genie and Marilyn Rigler.
    - Reel no. 419, 1975 May 2, 5 (Box 34, Folder 3)
      Genie and Baby Cory, eating cereal; electrodes. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 38.
    - No reel number given, 1975 May 2 (Box 34, Folder 4)
      Genie with Baby Cory.
    - No reel number given, 1975 June 24 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - No reel number given, 1975 June 24, 27 (Box 34, Folder 6)
      Larry Solow tests Genie on sign, continued.
    - Reel no. 420, 1975 June 27 (Box 34, Folder 7)
      Larry Solow finishes tests on Genie; counting pennies.
    - Reel no. 421, 1977 September 8 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Reel no. 422, 1977 September 15 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Reel no. 423, 1977 July 1 (Box 35, Folder 2)
      Genie and Mrs. Wiley; the Riglers.
    - Reel no. 424, 1977 January 15 (Box 35, Folder 3)
      Genie with the Riglers; dealing with vomiting. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 43.
    - Reel no. 425, 1974 December (Box 35, Folder 4)
      Susan Curtiss and T-Scope.
    - Reel no. 426, no date (Box 35, Folder 5)
      Genie with David Rigler.
    - Reel no. 427, 1977 June 27 (Box 35, Folder 6)
      Genie's angry session re: boy, mother, and milk carton. Tape has no sound.
    - Reel no. 428, 1974 December 20 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Reel no. 429, 1974 December (Box 35, Folder 8)
      Genie with T-Scope at Cal tech.
    - Reel no. 430, 1974 August 1 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Reel no. 431, 1974 December 30 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Reel no. 432, 1977 June 6 (Box 36, Folder 3)
      Angry session.
    - Reel no. 433, 1974 December 31 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Reel no. 434, 1974 December 30-31 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Reel no. 435, ca. 1974 December 4 (Box 36, Folder 6)
      Pre-test; T-Scope.
    - Reel no. 436, 1975 April (Box 36, Folder 7)
      Caroline talks about real mama; Genie tries hula hoops.
    - Reel no. 437, 1977 April 30 (Box 36, Folder 8)
      At rehabilitation with David Rigler. VHS cassette copy available for reference in box 43.
    - No reel number given, no date (Box 37, Folder 1)
      Genie uses a wagon taped to a spoon to feed herself ("wagon feed me").
    - No reel number given, no date (Box 37, Folder 2)
      Genie during sleep study, with electrodes.
    - Composite tape of segments no. 1, November through January, no date (Box 37, Folder 3)
      Sony 7" reel.
    - Composite tape of segments no. 2, January through March, no date (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Copies of UAP segments, 1970 November 23-24 (Box 37, Folder 5)
      Includes footage of H. Hansen and Mrs. Wiley; segments of James Kent, Mrs. Wiley, Genie, et al. Sony 7" reel.
  - 1B. VHS cassettes, 1970-1977; 6.5 boxes
    This subseries consists of VHS video cassettes. Most of the cassettes are numbered and correspond to the 1/2" tape reel numbers found in Subseries 1A. There are also eight VHS cassettes of Genie footage labeled WGBH. These contain some reformatted material off the 1/2" video tape reels, and possibly some original or composite footage gathered for the television show NOVA. The materials in this subseries may be consulted by researchers as reference viewing copies. All label and number information was transcribed directly off the cassette boxes to create a listing for the finding aid.
    - NOVA WGBH. Genie sews on Marilyn's sewing machine, tantrum, 1971, 1975 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      Television restoration from 1/2" tapes. Recorded 1975 January 29 and 1971 January 27.
    - NOVA WGBH. Genie sews on Marilyn's sewing machine, tantrum, 1971, 1975 (Box 38, Folder 2)
      Television restoration from 1/2" tapes. Recorded 1975 January 29 and 1971 January 27. With digital video noise reduction.
    - WGBH reference copy of 1/2" tape reel no. 2, 1970 December 1-2 (Box 38, Folder 3)
      Genie at window; rehabilitation talk show. Tape has no sound.